Haoyu He

Research Vision

My research interests lie within natural language processing with deep learning, including core NLP and interdisciplinary NLP research. Currently, I am broadly interested in the following topics: low-resource NLP, few-shot learning in NLP, multimodal understanding, language generation, and fact-checking. Besides, I am also open to other topics in NLP and deep learning.

Education

2020 – 2022 Msc in Artificial Intelligence, Northeastern University, Boston, USA. GPA: 3.4/4.0

Courses: Foundations of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Programming Design Paradigm, Human Computer Interaction, Natural Language Processing

2015 – 2019 **BEng in Computer Science and Technology**, Wuhan University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.

GPA: 3.2/4.0

Core Courses:

Algorithm Design and Analysis(A+), Mathematical Modeling (A+), Basics of Numerical Calculation(A), Linear Algebra(A), Probability and Mathematical Statistics(A), Advanced Mathematics(A), Image Processing(A)

Research Experience

Title Persuasive Robots for Health Behavior Change (In Progress)

Supervisor Prof. Timothy Bickmore

Description In this project, we will explore how a humanoid robot (Pepper) can persuade people to make healthy choices. The robot will interact with people by three modalities: hand gesture, speech, and image on its display. I will mainly focus on building strong conversational ability for the robot.

Title Automatic Text Simplification (ATS) Using Advanced Deep Learning Techniques

Supervisor Prof. Raman Chandrasekar

Description We proposed the first metrics to directly measure the sentence-to-sentence cohesion and meaning preservation for ATS outputs by taking advantage of pre-trained language models. We additionally provide a web app to visualize BERNICE and SAM results, you can find it here

.

Industrial Experience

2020.12-2021.9 Software Dev Engineer Intern, AWS AI Lab, Shanghai, China.

Worked as a research intern supervised by Dr.Xingjian Shi, researched knowledge distillation (KD) in NLP.

Detailed achievements:

- Proposed a meta-learning framework that can be used to learn the underpinning factors within the process of KD. Based on this framework, we conducted a systematic experimental study of KD in NLP and proposed a novel objective function to boost knowledge transfer.
- Aforementioned work was accepted at SustaiNLP 2021, EMNLP workshop. And an improved version of this paper was submitted to AAAI 2022 (Waiting for final decision).
- Contributed to the open-source library GluonNLP.
- 2020.5–2020.8 **NLP Research Intern**, *E-Capital Transfer Co.*, *Ltd.*, Shanghai, China. Studied semantic models and improved the performance of sentence similarity prediction in RASA-based conversational agents, a product in this company. Achieved in improving the accuracy of sentence similarity prediction task from 34% to 52% on the business dataset.
- 2019.10–2020.3 **NLP Engineering Intern**, *Ipsos (China) Consulting Co., Ltd.*, Shanghai, China.

Used NLP techniques to develop models which are used to analyze surveys and marketing reports.

Publications

[1] Haoyu He, Xingjian Shi, Jonas Mueller, Sheng Zha, Mu Li, and George Karypis. Distiller: A systematic study of model distillation methods in natural language processing. In *Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Simple and Efficient Natural Language Processing*, pages 119–133, Virtual, November 2021. Association for Computational Linguistics.

Languages

• Chinese (Native), English (Fluent)

Skills

- **Programming Languages**: Python, C/C++, Pytorch, Tensorflow.
- Tools & Software: Git, Linux, LATEX.
- English: TOEFL: 102, GRE: 152+170+3.5.